[MUSIC]
[Nǐ hǎo！Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.]
[Nǐ xǐhuɑn qù shānɡdiàn mɑ？Nǐ qù shānɡdiàn mǎi shénme dōnɡxi？Wǒ yǒushíhou qù shānɡdiàn mǎi shuǐɡuǒ. Shuǐɡuǒ hěn hǎochī，wǒ hěn xǐhuɑn chī shuǐɡuǒ. Nǐ ne？]
We're going to learn
three dialogues today.
They're all about buying things.
There are three new words
from the first dialogue.
Read after me, please.
[FOREIGN].
The basic unit of money in China is [yuán].
[kuài] is more common,
informal way to talk about money.
For example,
[yí kuài/yuán（qián）] [bā kuài/yuán（qián）]
[wǔ shí qī kuài/yuán（qián）]
To ask about price, you say
something first and then [Duōshao qián?].
For example, [FOREIGN].
[FOREIGN].
Now let's watch a video.
[Xiǎobèi xiǎnɡ mǎi pínɡɡuǒ.]
Please tell me how much is one apple.
How many apples did [Xiǎobèi] want to buy?
>> [FOREIGN]
>> Okay.
[Yí ɡè pínɡɡuǒ duōshǎo qián？]
[FOREIGN]
[Xiǎobèi mǎi le jǐ ɡè pínɡɡuǒ？]
[FOREIGN]. [Nǐ dá duì le mɑ？]
Read the text with me please.
[FOREIGN]
Dialogue two is about buying clothes.
Before watching video we will
learn a couple of new words.
Read after me please.
[FOREIGN]
[xiānshenɡ]
mister, sir, gentleman.[qiánmiàn] front.
[jiàn] is a measure word for clothes.
[Xùdōnɡ xiǎnɡ mǎi yí jiàn yīfu.]
Let's watch a video and tell me the prices
of the clothes [Xùdōnɡ] asked about.
>> [FOREIGN]
>> Okay, [Yīfu duōshao qián？]
Did you hear the first price is [jiǔ shí bā kuài].
The second price is [liù shí jiǔ kuài].
Follow me to read the text please. [FOREIGN].
[FOREIGN].
Now follow me to read dialogue three.
[FOREIGN]
again.
[mǐ] means uncooked rice. [mǐfàn] is cooked rice.
How about a bowl of rice
is [yì wǎn mǐ fàn].
[yì wǎn mǐ fàn].
I like eating rice
is [Wǒ xǐhuɑn chī m fà.] or [Wǒ ài chī mǐfàn.]
An exercise for you now.
Listen, choose the corresponding
picture for each dialogue.
>> Number one.
>> [FOREIGN]
Number two.
[FOREIGN]
>> [FOREIGN]
>> Number three.
>> Number four.
[FOREIGN]
>> [FOREIGN]
Number five.
>> Here are the texts.
And the answers here.
This type of question is
the same as that in part three
of the listening comprehension,
HSK, test level one.
There are five items.
The recording of each item
will be played twice.
A dialogue and several pictures
will be provided with each item.
You need to choose corresponding
pictures based on what you hear.
Okay, that's all for today.
[Xièxiè！Zàijiàn！]