[MUSIC]
[FOREIGN]
Today, we
are going
to learn
$2.
In the first of video [FOREIGN] and
Xiaopei are talking about
going to the university.
Listen to their conversation,
and answer questions.
>> [FOREIGN]
>> Okay, let's see the answers.
The first question,
how will Xiaopei go to university?
[FOREIGN] The second one,
how long will it take him to get there?
[FOREIGN].
Here is the text, read after me please.
[FOREIGN]
means
to drive
a car.
[FOREIGN] are come to drive,
[FOREIGN] has quite a few meanings.
For example, want, will,
shoot, shall, need.
The sentence [FOREIGN] means how
many minutes do you need to drive?
New words from dialogue two,
read after me please.
[FOREIGN]
apart from
expressing a learned
skill [FOREIGN]
can also be used
to indicate that
something will happen or
someone will do something.
For example, [FOREIGN]
means to listen.
[FOREIGN]
means to
hear, or heard.
[FOREIGN] is to return.
[FOREIGN] is home.
So [FOREIGN] is come back or go back home.
[FOREIGN] is take taxi.
The same meaning as
[FOREIGN]
is go back.
What about come back?
[FOREIGN]
I like walking.
Video time.
Listen to Tingna and Xiaopei.
Please pay attention to
the questions below.
>> [FOREIGN]
bbb
>> Okay, let's see the answers.
[FOREIGN]
Let's do an exercise now.
Based on the statements
questions are asked.
Listen and choose the correct
answer for each question.
>> Test 1,
[FOREIGN]
>> Question, [FOREIGN]
>> Test 2,
[FOREIGN]
>> Question, [FOREIGN]
>> Test 3,
[FOREIGN]
>> Question, [FOREIGN]
>> Test 4,
[FOREIGN]
>> Question [FOREIGN]
>> Test 5,
[FOREIGN]
>> Question,
>> Okay.
The answers are 1C,
2B, 3A, 4C, 5A.
[FOREIGN] This type of question
is the same as part four,
listening comprehension.
It is key tasks.
Level one,
their are five items in part four.
The recording of each item
would be played twice.
For each item,
a person will make a statement,
another person will then
ask the question and
provide three possible answers.
The three possible answers would
be listed on the test paper.
You need to choose one of the answers
based on what you hear.
[FOREIGN]