[MUSIC]
[Tónɡxuémen hǎo！Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.]
We learned family members such as
[bàbɑ, māmɑ, mèimei] last time.
Today, you will learn how to
talk about pets in Chinese and
[yǒu] sentence will be also introduced.
I guess the most popular pets
in the world are dogs and cats.
Dog is [ɡǒu],
cat is [māo] in Chinese.
Read with
me please, [FOREIGN]
[FOREIGN]
We learnt [dà] in [Nǐ duō dà?], How old are you?
but the basic meaning of [dà] is big.
So, [dà ɡǒu] is big dog.
[xiǎo] is small or little.
[xiǎo māo] is small cat.
How do you say, I have a dog,
I don't have a cat?
You say [Wǒ yǒu ɡǒu. Wǒ méiyǒu māo.]
[yǒu] means to have.
[méiyǒu] means don't have.
[yǒu] can be used in various ways.
But 'to have' is the most
basic meaning of this verb.
The structure is,
subject + [yǒu]
+ object,
for example,
[FOREIGN]
okay,
it's video time.
Let's listen to Xiaobei and
Xudong talking about their pets.
Please pay attention to
the questions below.
Who has a big dog?
Who has a small cat?
How old is the dog?
How old is the cat?
What is the name of the dog?
What is the name of the cat?
>> [FOREIGN]
>> Let's see the answers in Chinese.
[FOREIGN]
Let's have a look at the whole text.
Read after
me please, [FOREIGN]
[FOREIGN]
What is [ma] in
the question [Nǐ yǒu ɡǒu mɑ?]?
It's a yes or no question
marker in Chinese.
By placing [ma] at
the end of the statement,
you can convert it into a yes or
no question.
Simple and easy, isn't it?
[FOREIGN]
[zhī]is a measure
word used for
some animals
like rabbits,
tigers, ducks,
etc.
[FOREIGN]
Let's do an exercise.
Listening to two people
talking about their cats.
>> [FOREIGN]
>> Let's see the answers.
The man has a cat.
The dog's name is Dōngdong.
Who is 5 years old?
Lìli.
If you have a pet, you may want to
give him or her a Chinese name now.
Time to say bye-bye.
Hope you enjoyed the lesson.
[Xièxie! Zàijiàn!]