[MUSIC]
[Nǐ hǎo！Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.]
[Nǐ yǒu jiějie mɑ？Tā zuò shénme ɡōnɡzuò？Tā shì yīshēnɡ mɑ？]
[Nǐ xiǎnɡ zài yīyuàn ɡōnɡzuò mɑ？] [Wǒ yǒu yí ɡè jiějie.]
[Tā bú shì yī shenɡ. Wǒ yě yǒu yí ɡè dìdi hé yí ɡè mèimei.]
[Tāmen dōu bú shì yīshēnɡ.] In this lesson,
we're going to talk about what you like or dislike.
[Nǐ xǐhuɑn zuò shénme? Nǐ bù xǐhuɑn zuò shénme？]
[Wǒ xǐhuɑn kànshū，nǐ ne？]
Let's learn some new words first.
Follow me please.
[FOREIGN]
[kāfēi] is coffee.
[tīnɡ] means hall or room.
[nàlǐ], there.
You could also say [nàr].
You may remember here is [zhèlǐ] or
[zhèr]. [kànshū] to read a book, reading.
[shū] means book.
For reading, we also say [dúshū].
[běn], measure words for books.
We can say, [yì běn shū，yì běn hǎo shū].
[zhōnɡwén], Chinese language.
Another word for Chinese is [hànyǔ].
[hǎokàn],
good looking.
You could say [Tā hěn hǎokàn.].
Also [hǎokàn] means interesting.
You could say [Zhè běn shū hěn hǎokàn.].
[Hónɡlóumènɡ],
The English translation is
A Dream of Red Mansions.
A very famous novel in China.
Video time.
Kaili and
Qiaozhi are chatting on Wechat.
Listen and tell me
[Tāmen xǐhuɑn shénme?] [Tāmen bù xǐhuɑn shénme?].
>> [FOREIGN]
>> What did you
hear from their
conversation?
[FOREIGN]
[FOREIGN] the last question,
I know it's not easy for you to get all the answers correct, because there's quite
a lot of information.
But I'm sure you could understand
more after reading the text.
Okay, read with me please.
[FOREIGN]
Okay, let's do an exercise now.
Right now we are all in
different places in the world.
Can you please tell me [FOREIGN]?
[FOREIGN]
If you ask me the same questions,
I could say [FOREIGN]
[FOREIGN]
[FOREIGN] Okay, time is up.
Looking forward to seeing you next time.
[xièxie！Zàijiàn!]