[MUSIC]
[Nǐ hǎo！Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.]
[Nǐ yǒu jiějie mɑ? Tā zuò shénme ɡōnɡzuò?
Tā shì yīshēnɡ mɑ?]
[Nǐ xiǎnɡ zài yīyuàn ɡōnɡzuò mɑ?]
[Wǒ yǒu yí ɡè jiějie.]
[Tā bú shì yīshenɡ. Wǒ yě yǒu yí ɡè dìdi
hé yí ɡè mèimei.]
[Tāmen dōu bú shì yīshēnɡ.] In this lesson,
we're going to talk about what you like or dislike.
[Nǐ xǐhuɑn zuò shénme? Nǐ bù xǐhuɑn zuò shénme?]
[Wǒ xǐhuɑn kànshū，nǐ ne?]
Let's learn some new words first.
Follow me please.
[kāfēi tīng] [nàlǐ/nàr]
[kànshū/dúshū] [běn]
[zhōngwén] [hǎokàn] [hónglóumèng]
[kāfēi tīng], café. [kāfēi] is coffee.
[tīnɡ] means hall or room.
[nàlǐ], there.
You could also say [nàr].
You may remember, here is [zhèlǐ] or
[zhèr]. [kànshū] to read a book, reading.
[shū] means book.
For reading, we also say [dúshū].
[běn], measure words for books.
We can say, [Yì běn shū]
[Yì běn hǎoshū].
[zhōnɡwén], Chinese language.
Another word for Chinese is [hànyǔ].
[hǎokàn], good looking.
You could say [Tā hěn hǎokàn.].
You could say [Tā hěn hǎokàn].
Also [hǎokàn] means interesting.
You could say [Zhè běn shū hěn hǎokàn].
[Hónɡlóumènɡ], the English translation
is A Dream of Red Mansions.
A very famous novel in China.
Video time.
Kaili and Qiaozhi are chatting on Wechat.
Listen and tell me, [Tāmen xǐhuɑn shénme?]
[Tāmen bù xǐhuɑn shénme?]
>> [Kǎilì, nǐ zài nǎr ne?]
>> [Wǒ zài kāfēi tīng ne.[]
>> [Nǐ zài nǎlǐ zuò shénme ne?]
>> [Wǒ kàn shū ne.]
>> [Ó, shén me shū?]
>> [Yī běn zhōngwén shū, jiào hóng lóu mèng.]
>> [Hǎo kàn ma?]
>> [En, hěn hǎokàn.]
[Wǒ xǐ huān kàn zhòngwén shū,
nǐ zài kàn shén me shū?]
>> [Wǒ bù xǐhuān kànshū.]
[Wǒ xǐhuān shuìjiào hé kàn diànshì.]
What did you hear from their
conversation?
[Kǎilì zài nǎr ne?]
[Kǎilì zài kāfēi tīng ne.]
[Kǎilì zuò shénme ne?]
[Kǎilì kànshū ne.]
[Shū de míngzì shì shénme?]
[Hónglóumèng.]
[Kǎilì xǐhuān kàn shénme shū?]
[Tā xǐhuān kàn zhòngwén shū.]
[Qiáozhì xǐhuān kànshū ma?]
[Bù xǐhuān.]
The last question,
[Qiáozhì xǐhuān zuò shénme?]
[Qiáozhì xǐhuān shuìjiào hé kàn diànshì.]
I know it's not easy for you to get all the answers
correct, because there's quite a lot of information.
But I'm sure you could understand
more after reading the text.
Okay, read with me please.
>> [Kǎilì, nǐ zài nǎr ne?]
>> [Wǒ zài kāfēi tīng ne.]
>> [Nǐ zài nǎlǐ zuò shénme ne?]
>> [Wǒ kàn shū ne.]
>> [Ó, shén me shū?]
>> [Yī běn zhōngwén shū, jiào hóng lóu mèng.]
>> [Hǎokàn ma?]
>> [En, hěn hǎokàn.]
[Wǒ xǐhuān kàn zhòngwén shū,
nǐ zài kàn shén me shū?]
>> [Wǒ bù xǐhuān kànshū.]
[Wǒ xǐhuān shuìjiào hé kàn diànshì.]
Okay, let's do an exercise now.
Right now we are all in
different places in the world.
Can you please tell me,
[nǐ zài nǎ ér ne?]
[Nǐ zuò shénme ne?]
[Nǐ xǐhuān zuò shénme?]
[Nǐ bù xǐhuān zuò shénme?]
If you ask me the same questions,
I could say
[Wǒ zài běijīng ne.]
[Wǒ jiāo hànyǔ ne.]
[Wǒ xǐhuān kàn diànyǐng.]
[Wǒ bù xǐhuān dǎ májiàng.]
Okay, time is up.
Looking forward to seeing you next time.
[Xièxie！Zàijiàn!]