[MUSIC]
[Nǐ hǎo！Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ. Nǐ zuò shénme ɡōnɡzuò？Nǐ shì lǎoshī mɑ？Nǐ de xuéshenɡ duō mɑ？Nǐ bàbɑ、māmɑ zài nǎr ɡōnɡzuò？Nǐ xiǎnɡ qù wàiɡuó ɡōnɡzuò mɑ？]
In this lesson,
we are talking about more jobs.
The topic of this
lesson is [FOREIGN].
Firstly, let's learn some new words.
There are three words related to hospital.
[FOREIGN]
[zuótiān] is yesterday.
Do you remember today and tomorrow?
Yes, today is [jīntiān].
Tomorrow is [mínɡtiān].
So [zuótiān], [jīntiān], [mínɡtiān].
[kànjiàn]
means to catch sight of or to see.
We have learned [kàn] in [kàn diànshì] and [jiàn] in [zàijiàn].
How do you translate,
I saw a cat in your school?
You could say [Wǒ zài nǐ de xuéxiào kànjiàn yì zhī māo. ]
I caught sights of your younger
brother in the hospital.
[Wǒ zài yīyuàn kànjiàn le nǐ dìdi.]
[jiějie] elder sister. For family members,
now you know, [bàbɑ, māmɑ, ɡēɡe],
[dìdi, jiějie]
[hé] [mèimei].
[diànyǐnɡyuàn]
Cinema.
[Tāmen zài diànyǐnɡyuàn kàn diànyǐnɡ.]
[ǹg], like [ò], it expresses
exclamation of various kinds of emotional response.
You could hear a lot in daily life,
if you are in China.
For example,
[FOREIGN].
Now we are going to watch a video.
Listen to Huanhuan and Hailiang and
pay attention to the questions below.
>> [FOREIGN].
>> [FOREIGN]
>> Okay.
Let's see the answers.
[Huānhuān de jiějie zài nǎr ɡōnɡzuò？]
[Zài yīyuàn. ]
[Tā shì yīshēnɡ mɑ?]
[Duì，tā shì yīshēnɡ.]
[Tā xǐhuɑn tā de ɡōnɡzuò mɑ?]
[Tā hěn xǐhuɑn.]
Number four.
[Huānhuān xiǎnɡ zài yīyuàn ɡōnɡzuò mɑ？] [Tā bù xiǎnɡ.]
The last one.
[Tā xiǎnɡ zài nǎr ɡōnɡzuò？] [Zài diànyǐnɡyuàn.]
Here is the whole text.
Read after me please.
[FOREIGN].
Okay, let's do an exercise. Reading:
Look at the words and the pictures.
True or false?
[FOREIGN] Are you correct?
This question type is the same as part
one of level one HSK reading test.
There are five items in part one.
Each item provides a picture and
a word or phrase,
you need to judge whether or
not they are consistent with each other.
That's all for today,
hope you enjoyed the lesson.
[Xièxie! Zàijiàn!]