Hello, welcome to Chinese for HSK.
My name is YU Bin.
Nice to meet you.
Wo jiao YU Bin. For the first week of your Chinese study,
we'll talk about greetings and numbers.
In this lesson, we're going to learn how to greet
people and how to ask somebody's name in Chinese.
Firstly, let's watch a short video and
see what people say when they meet for the first time.
Here come Xudong and Tingna.
Ni hao.
Ni jiao shenme mingzi?
Wo jiao tigna
Wo jiao Xudong.
Hen gaoxing renshi ni.
Cannot understand much?
Don't worry. I'm sure you'll be okay at the end of this lesson.
You may have known that's the most commonly used phrase for
greetings in Chinese is ni hao, hello.
Ni means you, hao means good.
So, ni hao literally means you good.
However, ni hao is rarely used among very close friends or families.
Ni and hao about third tone when two-third tones are read in sequence,
the first syllable turns into the second term.
So, ni hao it's read ni hao rather than ni hao.
Although, you need to mark it at third tone in writing.
Follow me please, ni hao, ni hao.
One day, we may meet up somewhere in the world.
How do you greet me?
You may say, ni hao!
Yu laoshi!
I say to you, for example,
ni hao Jenny, ni hao Lucy, ni hao David.
To ask somebody's name in Chinese is ni jiao shenme mingzi?
Literally, your quote what name,
jiao means to call,
shenme is what, mingzi is name.
To respond, you say wo jiao followed by your name.
Unlike English, the question word,
shenme is usually placed after the verb in the sentence.
Sometimes, a noun such as a person,
a book, or name follows it.
Now, read with me jiao, jiao,
shenma, shenme, mingzi, mingzi, wo, wo.
Ni jiao shenme mingzi?
Wo jiao, wo jiao. Let's do an exercise now.
Match the Chinese words with pictures or English words.
Let's say it together.
Ni hao. Which one? Yeah, here.
Mingzi, jiao,
this one, shenme.
Did you get it? One more sentence
for you is hen gaoxing renshi ni, nice to meet you.
Literally, it means very happy to know you.
Read after me, please.
Hen, hen, gaoxing, gaoxing, renshi,
renshi, hen gaoxing renshi ni,
hen gaoxing renshi mi.
Reads the text of the video with me, please.
Ni hao!
Ni jiao shenme mingzi?
Wo jiao tingna.
Ni jiao shenme mingzi.
Wo jiao Xudong.
Hen gaoxing renshi ni.
Han gaoxing renshi ni.
Now, listen to a conversation between two people,
two questions for you.
Ni hao. Wo jiao Bide.
Hen gaoxing renshi ni.
Okay? Let's see the answers.
The man's name, Bide,
Bide, and the woman's name,
Mali, Mali.
Are you correct? That's all for today.
I hope you enjoyed lesson. Thank you.
Bye bye. Xiexie. Zaijian.