[Tónɡxuémen hǎo! Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.]
[Nǐ xiǎnɡ qù Shànɡhǎi mɑ? Nǐ xiǎnɡ lái Běijīnɡ mɑ?
Shànɡhǎi dà mɑ? Běijīnɡ rén duō mɑ?]
Wǒ yǒu hěn duō Zhōnɡɡuó pénɡyou,
yě yǒu hěn duō wàiɡuó pénɡyou.]
[Nǐ ne?] We're going to watch a video.
Before we do, we will learn some new words.
Read with me please.
[shàngeèyuè] [qián] [nǎr]  [xǐhuan] [hǎochī]
[dōu] [bīngmǎyǒng] [xī'ān] [xiānggǎng]
[qián] is before or ago.
When you use [qián], the order
is different from English.
For example, before going to Xi'an,
[qù Xī’ān qián]. Before having dinner,
[chīfàn qián]. A month ago,
[yí ɡe yuè qián].
[nǎr] means where.
As other wh- words,
the structure of [nǎr] is
subject plus verb plus [nǎlǐ] or [nǎr],
the same meaning.
For example, [Nǐ qù nǎr?]
[Wǒ qù Xiānɡɡǎnɡ.]
Video time now.
Listen to the conversation
between Xudong and Xiaobei, and
thinking about the questions below.
>> [Xiǎobèi, zhè shì nǎr?]
>> [Xī'ān, shànggèyuè wǒ qù xī'ān le.]
>> [Qù xī'ān qián nǐ qù nǎr le?]
>> [Qù xī'ān qián wǒ qù xiānggǎng le.]
>> [Xī'ān zěnme yàng?]
>> [Hěnhǎo, wǒ xǐhuān kàn bīngmǎyǒng.]
>> [Xiāng gǎng ne?]
>> [Xiānggǎng de fàn hěn hǎochī.]
>> [Shìma? Wǒ yě xiǎng qù.
Xī'ān hé xiānggǎng de tiānqì zěn me yàng?]
>> [Xī'ān hé xiānggǎng de tiānqì dōu hěn rè.]
Okay, number one.
[Shànɡ ɡè yuè shéi qù le Xī'ān?]
[Xiǎobèi.]
[Qù Xī'ān qián tā qù nǎr le?] [Xiānɡɡǎnɡ.]
[Tā xǐhuɑn Xī'ān de shénme?]
[Bīnɡmǎyǒnɡ.]
What did she mention about Hong Kong?
Number four, [Fàn, Xiānɡɡǎnɡ de fàn.]
[Xī'ān hé Xiānɡɡǎnɡ de tiānqì zěnmeyànɡ?]
[Dōu hěn rè.]
If you don't understand well about
their conversation, don't worry.
Follow me and read the whole text.
>> [Xiǎobèi, zhè shì nǎr?]
>> [Xī'ān shànggèyuè wǒ qù xī'ān le.]
>> [Qù xī'ān qián nǐ qù nǎr le?]
>> [Qù xī'ān qián wǒ qù xiānggǎng le.]
>> [Xī'ān zěnme yàng?]
>> [Hěnhǎo, wǒ xǐhuān kàn bīngmǎyǒng.]
>> [Xiāng gǎng ne?]
>> [Xiānggǎng de fàn hěn hǎochī.]
>> [Shìma? Wǒ yě xiǎng qù!
Xī'ān hé xiānggǎng de tiān qì zěn me yàng?]
>> [Xī'ān hé xiānggǎng dōu hěn rè.]
I'm sure you understand better now.
That's all for today.
Hope you enjoyed the lesson.
[Xièxie! Zàijiàn!]