[MUSIC]
[Tónɡxuémen hǎo！Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.]
[Nǐ xiǎnɡ qù Shànɡhǎi mɑ？Nǐ xiǎnɡ lái Běijīnɡ mɑ？Shànɡhǎi dà mɑ？Běijīnɡ rén duō mɑ？]
Wǒ yǒu hěn duō Zhōnɡɡuó pénɡyou，yě yǒu hěn duō wàiɡuó pénɡyou.]
[Nǐ ne？] We're going to watch a video.
Before we do, we will learn some new words.
Read with me please.
[FOREIGN]
[qián] is before or ago.
When you use [qián] the order
is different from English.
For example, before going to Xi' an,
[qù Xī’ān qián]. Before having dinner,
[chīfàn qián].
A month ago,
[yí ɡe yuè qián]
[nǎr] means where.
As other wh words,
the structure of [nǎr] is, a subject
plus verb plus [nǎlǐ] or [nǎr],
the same meaning.
For example,
[Nǐ qù nǎr？] [Wǒ qù Xiānɡɡǎnɡ.]
Video time now.
Listen to the conversation
between Xudong and Xiaobei and
think about the questions below.
>> [FOREIGN]
>> Okay, number one.
[Shànɡ ɡè yuè shéi qù le Xī'ān？]
[Xiǎobèi.]
[Qù Xī'ān qián tā qù nǎr le？] [Xiānɡɡǎnɡ].
[Tā xǐhuɑn Xī'ān de shénme？]
[Bīnɡmǎyǒnɡ.]
What did she mention about Hong Kong?
Number four, [fàn], [Xiānɡɡǎnɡ de fàn.]
[Xī'ān hé Xiānɡɡǎnɡ de tiānqì zěnmeyànɡ?]
[Dōu hěn rè.]
If you don't understand well about
their conversation, don't worry.
Follow me and read the whole text.
[FOREIGN]
I'm sure you understand better now.
That's all for today.
Hope you enjoyed the lesson.
[Xièxie! Zàijiàn!]