[MUSIC]
[Nǐ hǎo！Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ. Jīntiān nǐ qù shānɡdiàn le mɑ？Nǐ mǎi pínɡɡuǒ le mɑ？Yí ɡè pínɡɡuǒ duōshao qián？Nǐ xǐhuɑn mǎi yīfu mɑ？Wǒ xǐhuɑn chī pínɡɡuǒ，yě xǐhuɑn chī mǐfàn, nǐ ài chī shénme？].
Today we're going to talk about
buying things on the Internet.
[Zài wǎnɡshànɡ mǎi dōnɡxi.] is very popular in China now.
What about in your country?
Read the new words with me please.
[FOREIGN].
[wǎnɡshanɡ] is online or on the Internet.
[chá] is tea.
[zěnme shuō] Chinese tea?
[Zhōnɡɡuó chá]. [bēizi] is cup.
[zěnme shuō] tea cup?
[chábēi]. [xué] is study or learn.
It's the same meaning as [xuéxí].
I learn English, you learn Chinese
[zěnme shuō]? [Wǒ xué hànyǔ，nǐ xué yīnɡyǔ].
[kéyǐ] means can or may.
Can I sit here?
[Wǒ kěyǐ zuò zhèr mɑ？]
may I speak Chinese?
[Wǒ kěyǐ shuō hànyǔ mɑ?]
[hǎo bɑ] is like
[hǎo de], [hǎo], means okay, all right.
For example, [Wǒmen tīnɡ yīnyuè bɑ!]
[Hǎo bɑ!].
Video time, listen to Huanhuan and
Hailiang, talking about stopping online.
>> [FOREIGN]
>> Okay, let's see the answers.
[Hǎiliànɡ zuótiān zài wǎnɡshanɡ mǎi le shénme？]
[chá，bēizi hé yì běn shū]. [Shū de mínɡzi shì shénme?] [Zhōnɡɡuó cài.] [Huānhuān xiǎnɡ xuéxí shénme？] [Tā xiǎnɡ xué zuò Zhōnɡɡuó cài.]
The next one.
How long?
[yí ɡè yuè].
The last one
[shì de] or [duì].
Now lets read the whole text.
[FOREIGN].
[wǎnɡshanɡ] is online.
If you say [shànɡwǎnɡ] it
means to surf the Internet.
Look at the character [wǎnɡ].
Is it really like a net?
The particle [le]
has many uses, one of
the most common is to
express the completion
of an action. This is called aspect,
Which is about whether the action
is complete in the certain time.
The structure is subject
+ verb + [le] + object.
For example
[FOREIGN]
Let’s do an exercise.
Please make a sentence or
phrase based on each picture.
Number one, [Tāmen zài mǎi shuǐɡuǒ.]
or you could say, [Tāmen mǎi le shuǐɡuǒ].
The second one,
[Tāmen zài xué zuò Zhōnɡɡuó cài].
The last one.
[Tāmen zài hēchá.]
Time to say bye-bye. See you next time.
[Xièxie！Zàijiàn！]