[MUSIC]
[Tónɡxuémen hǎo！Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.]
[Jīntiān shì jǐ yuè jǐ hào？Jīntiān xīnɡqī jǐ？]
[Nǐ de shēnɡrì shì jǐ yuè jǐ hào？]
'Happy birthday!' [zěnme shuō]?
Can you sing the song
'happy birthday' in Chinese?
In this lesson we're going
to learn some new words and
expressions about weather in Chinese.
Listen to dialogue one.
>> [Míngtiān tiānqì zěnmeyàng？]
>> [Bùtàihǎo, míngtiān yǒu yǔ.]
What are they talking about?
Yes, the weather.
Let's read the text.
>> [Míngtiān tiānqì zěnmeyàng？]
>> [Bùtàihǎo, míngtiān yǒu yǔ.]
[tiānqì] is weather.[yǔ] Is rain.
The meaning of the question is
what is the weather like tomorrow?
And the answer, word by
word, is not very good.
Tomorrow has rain.
Read again with me, please.
>> [Míngtiān tiānqì zěnmeyàng？]
>> [Bùtàihǎo, míngtiān yǒu yǔ.]
Now listen to dialogue two.
>> [Xiàyǔ le!]
>> [Shén me! Xiàyǔ le? Wǒ de diànnǎo zài wàimiàn ne!]
From the picture,
you may guess what is happening now.
Yes, it's raining, but
the computer is outside.
Read the text with me, please.
>> [Xiàyǔ le!]
>> [Shén me! Xiàyǔ le? Wǒ de diànnǎo zài wàimiàn ne!]
Again.
>> [Xiàyǔ le!]
>> [Shén me! Xiàyǔ le? Wǒ de diànnǎo zài wàimiàn ne!]
[Xià yǔ le] means it's raining,
like we learned some time ago,
[le] indicates change of situation or
starting a new situation.
[diànnǎo] is computer and
[wàimiàn] is outside.
In a sentence [Wǒ de diànnǎo zài wàimiàn ne!],
[zài] is a verb,
expressing existence in a location,
similar to how we say in
English, 'to be at' or 'to be in'.
For example, [Wǒ zài běi jīng.]
[Tā zài shàng hǎi.]
In dialogue three,
it mentions two places in China.
One is Guangzhou, a big city in Southern China.
Harbin a city in the Northeast.
Let's learn some new words.
[rè] [lěng] [yǒu diǎnr] [guǎngzhōu] [hā'ěrbīn]
We're going to listen to dialogue three.
Pay attention to the weather
in the two cities.
>> [Guǎngzhōu de tiānqì zěnmeyàng?]
>> [Tài rè le.]
>> [hā'ěr bīn ne?]
>> [Yǒu diǎnr lěng.]
[Guǎnɡzhōu de tiānqì zěnmeyànɡ?]
The answer? [Tài rè le!]
[Hā'ěrbīn de tiānqì zěnmeyànɡ?]
[Yǒu diǎnr lěnɡ.]
[yǒu diǎnr] is a little, a bit.
Usually indicating something unpleasant or
undesired.
The structure is [yǒu diǎnr] + adjective
or psychological verb.
Examples here.
[Tiānqì yǒudiǎnr rè.]
[Wǒ de péngyǒu yǒu diǎnr bù gāoxìng.]
Read the whole text of dialogue
three with me, please.
>> [Guǎngzhōu de tiānqì zěnmeyàng?]
>> [Tài rè le.]
>> [Hā'ěr bīn ne?]
>> [Yǒu diǎnr lěng.]
An exercise for you.
Listen.
Number 1
[Xiàyǔ le.]
Number 2
[Yǒu diǎnr lěng.]
Number 3
[Wǒ de shēngrì]
Number 4
[Dǎ diànhuà]
Number 5
[Wàimiàn hěn lěng]
Okay, let's see the answers.
[Nǐ dá duì le mɑ？]
Are you correct?
That's all for today.
Hope you enjoyed the lesson.
[Xièxie! Zàijiàn!]