[MUSIC]
[Tónɡxuémen hǎo！Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.]
[Nǐ ài kàn diànshì mɑ？Nǐ xǐhuɑn kàn diànyǐnɡ mɑ？]
[Nǐ xǐhuɑn dǎqiú mɑ？Nǐ xǐhuɑn tīnɡ yīnyuè mɑ? ]
[Wǒ ài kàn zhònɡɡuó diànyǐnɡ，yě xǐhuɑn kàn wàiɡuó diànyǐnɡ. Nǐ ne？]
In this lesson, we will watch a video，
Xiaobei and Xiaopei
are talking about a friend.
Let's go over the new words first.
[FOREIGN]
[FOREIGN] [qǐnɡ zuò], please sit down.
[qǐnɡ] is please.
[zuò] is to sit.
[Qǐnɡ hē kāfēi.] Please drink coffee.
[shǒujī] mobile phone.
[shǒu] is hand.
[jī] is machine.
So literally,
[shǒujī] means hand machine.
[tīnɡ] listen or hear.
[tīnɡ yīnyuè] listen to music.
[Tīnɡ lǎoshī shuō hànyǔ.] Listen to the teacher
speaking Chinese.
[yīnyuè] is music.
[shūdiàn] Book shop.
[shū] is book.
[diàn] is shop.
[xiǎoxué] primary school.
Do you remember [xiǎoxué shēnɡ]?
Primary school student.
Okay, video time.
Listen carefully.
Pay attention to the questions below.
>> [FOREIGN]
>> Okay, let's have a look.
[Xiǎobèi de pénɡyou xǐhuɑn zuò shénme？] [FOREIGN]
[Xiǎopéi rènshi tā mɑ？][FOREIGN]
[Zhè ɡe pénɡyou jiào shénme mínɡzi?] [FOREIGN]
[Tā zài nǎr ɡōnɡzuò?][FOREIGN]
The last one.
[Tā shì shéi de pénɡyou？]
[FOREIGN]
How many did you get?
Now follow me to read the whole text.
[FOREIGN].
[qǐnɡ] is a verb used
before another verb to form
an imperative sentence
indicating a polite suggestion.
For example, [Qǐnɡ zuò],
Sit down please.
[Qǐnɡ shuō hànyǔ.]
or [Qǐnɡ shuō zhōnɡwén.]
Please speak Chinese.
How do you say, please give me a call?
[Qǐnɡ ɡěi wǒ dǎ diànhuà].
Let's go on with the text.
[FOREIGN]
An exercise for you now,
match the statements with the pictures.
Have a look at the pictures here and
the statements.
You could follow me,
to read those statements.
Number 1,
[FOREIGN].
Number 2,
Number 3, [FOREIGN].
Number 4, [FOREIGN].
Number 5, [FOREIGN].
Okay, the answers are here.
1C, [shǒujī].
2A [diànshì].
3B [dǎqiú.].
4E [shūdiàn].
5D
[yīnyuè, tīnɡ yīnyuè].[Nǐ dá duì le mɑ？]
This type of question is
the same as in reading
comprehension part two HSK Level One.
There are five items in Part Two.
The test paper will
display several pictures.
For each item,
a sentence will be provided.
You need to choose one of
the corresponding pictures based on
the content of the sentence.
Time to say bye-bye.
Hope you enjoyed lesson.
[Xièxiè！Zàijiàn！]