[MUSIC]
[FOREIGN]
HSK
[FOREIGN].
In this lesson we are going
to learn a short text.
Let's watch a video.
>> [FOREIGN]
>> The good
news is that we don't have many
new words in the conversation.
Can you choose the correct answer for
each question?
The boy in the picture is Tingna's
[FOREIGN].
Number 2, the girl in the picture
is Tingna's [FOREIGN]
Number 3, The animal they mentioned
at the end of the video is [FOREIGN].
Please don't worry if you got some
wrong answers, they talked very fast.
Let's go through the text then.
Read with me please.
[FOREIGN].
[FOREIGN]
A couple of new words for you,
[FOREIGN] is friend.
[FOREIGN] means to look,
to see, to watch or to read.
To read a book, [FOREIGN] is film.
[FOREIGN] is today.
[FOREIGN] means want to or would like to.
And the film's name is,
[FOREIGN], Kung Fu Panda.
Let's do an exercise now.
Listen, and then decide true or false.
Number 1
[FOREIGN].
Number 2
Number 3
[FOREIGN].
Number 4
Number 5 [FOREIGN].
Let's see the answers.
[FOREIGN], are you correct?
The question type of
the exercise we have just done
is the same as part of
the listening test HSK Level 1.
I will introduce more question types for
you later.
That's all for today.
See you next week.
[FOREIGN]