[MUSIC]
Hello, welcome to HSK Chinese.
[Nǐ hǎo！Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.]
[Wǒ jiào Yú Bīn. Hěn ɡāoxìnɡ rènshi nǐ.]
[Nǐ jiào shénme mínɡzi？]
[Nǐ shì nǎ ɡuó rén?] Today we are going to learn how to ask about nationality in Chinese.
Where are you from or
what's your nationality, is [Nǐ shì nǎ ɡuó rén?].
In Chinese [shì] is to be,
[nǎ] is which.
[ɡuó] means country or nation.
[rén] is person or people.
Word by word is,
you are which country person.
Read after me please.
[FOREIGN] Does the word
order in the sentence weird? Not really!
It's the same as [Nǐ jiào shénme míngzi?] a subject,
a verb, a question word, and a noun.
If you ask me [Nǐ shì nǎ ɡuórén?]
I will tell you [Wǒ shì Zhōnɡɡuórén.]
I'm Chinese.
[Zhōnɡɡuó] is China.
So to talk about nationality in Chinese
you just add ren after the name of the country.
For example, American is [Měiɡuórén].
Japanese is [Rìběnrén].
Please pay attention to [shì].
Chinese verbs do not have inflections,
that is, the form of the verb is the same,
no matter what the subject is.
For example,
in the sentences, [FOREIGN]
the verb is always [shì]
never changes.
Read after me please.
[FOREIGN]
again,
[FOREIGN].
Let's watch a video now.
Listen to [Xùdōnɡ ] and
[Kǎilì] carefully.
Tell me where they are from.
>> [FOREIGN]
>> [FOREIGN] [FOREIGN]
>> An exercise for you.
Match the people in the video
with their nationalities.
Okay?
[FOREIGN]
And the girl
with the book,
[FOREIGN].
Are you correct?
The last dialog in the video
is, the question [FOREIGN] and
the answer, [FOREIGN].
[tā] means she.
[yě] means also.
The question is, where is she from?
And Xudong said, she is also Chinese.
Different from English,
[yě] is placed before a verb.
You can't put it after a verb or
at the end of a sentence.
Moreover, if you say [Me too.]
You can't say [wǒ yě] but [wǒ yě shì].
Read with me again.
[FOREIGN]
Okay, that's all for today.
Don't forget your quiz for the lesson.
[Xièxie! Zàijiàn!]