[MUSIC]
[Nǐ hǎo！Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.]
[Nǐ xǐhuɑn zuò shénme ɡōnɡzuò?]
[Nǐ de bàbɑ, māmɑ, ɡēɡe, jiějie, dìdi, mèimei]
[ài kàn diànyǐnɡ mɑ?
Nǐ de hǎo pénɡyou xǐhuɑn tīnɡ yīnyuè mɑ?]
We learned work and hobbies last week.
In this week,
we will talk about shopping and food.
The first lesson is [Qù shānɡdiàn].
Read the new words with me please.
[shāngdiàn] [mǎi]
[dōngxi] [yīxiē]
[shuǐguǒ] [jiàn]
[FOREIGN] let's watch a video.
Listen to Xiaobei and
Tingna talking about shopping.
Tell me where they're going and
what they are going to do.
>> [FOREIGN]
>> Okay, questions?
[Xiǎobèi qù nǎr？]
[Tā qù shānɡdiàn. ]
[Tínɡnà qù nǎr？]
[Tā qù jiàn yí ɡe tónɡxué.] Okay, read the text with me.
[FOREIGN]
[Nǐ qù nǎr？] is sort of greetings in Chinese culture.
You may not really want
to know where he or
she is going but
just to show your concern.
Usually, when you see somebody doing something like studying,
shopping, eating, you may ask, [Xuéxí ne？Mǎi dōnɡxi ne？]
[Chīfàn ne？].
Actually, this kind of conversation
is mainly for greetings,
not for exchanging information.
In Chinese culture, restating a fact effect in
a question way, is a way of greeting.
[Xiǎobèi shuō,] [Wǒ qù shānɡdiàn mǎi dōnɡxi.]
This sentence contains two verbs [qù] and [mǎi],
like I introduced to you before.
It is a sentence with serial verbs.
[xiǎnɡ] is a very useful word.
It can be used to express would like to.
In this case, it's an auxiliary verb
in the conversation, [Tínɡnà shuō]
[Nǐ xiǎnɡ mǎi shénme dōnɡxi？]
[Xiǎobèi shuō, wǒ xiǎnɡ mǎi yìxiē shuǐɡuǒ.]
And the structure is,
subject plus [xiǎnɡ] plus verb plus object.
We had [xiǎnɡ] in
previous lesson as well.
For example, [FOREIGN].
[FOREIGN].
How do you say I'd like
to have a Chinese dish?
[FOREIGN]
How about,
I don't want to see that person.
[FOREIGN].
Let's do an exercise,
match the phrases with the pictures.
Let's have a look.
Okay.
[FOREIGN].
That's all for today.
I hope you enjoyed the lesson.
[Xièxie！Zàijiàn！]