[MUSIC]
[Tónɡxuémen hǎo! Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.]
[Wǒmen xuéxí le shànɡmiàn, xiàmiàn,
qiánmiàn, hòumiàn]
[lǐmiàn, wàimiàn] Can you use
these direction words to make some sentences?
[Qǐnɡ tīnɡ wǒ shuō.]
[Wǒ de xiǎo māo zài zhuōzi shànɡmiàn.
Wǒ de shū zài yǐzi xiàmiàn.]
[Shǒujī zài nǐ de shūbāo lǐmiàn.]
[Nǐ de pénɡyou zài xuéxiào wàimiàn.]
[Tā de tónɡxué zài shānɡdiàn lǐmiàn.]
[Tā jiā zài wǒ jiā hòumiàn.]
[Nǐ tīnɡdǒnɡ le mɑ?] Do you understand?
I am actually confused by those words and the sentences.
Anyway, you will have something new for
today, the topic for this lesson is
[Tài měi le!] So beautiful!
Tingna and Hailiang
are talking about the Great Wall.
Listen carefully and
pay attention to the questions below.
>> [Zhè shì bādálǐng chángchéng ma?] >> [Shì a.]
>> [Tài měi le! Bādálǐng chángchéng zài nǎr?]
>> [Zài běijīng de xīběi.
Wǒmen jiào jǐ gè tóngxué yīqǐ qù ba?]
>> [Hǎo a! Nǎtiān qù?]
>> [Zhège xīngqīliù zěnme yàng?]
>> [Hǎo, wǒmen zěnme qù ne?]
>> [Nǐ xué chē le ma? Wǒmen kāichē qù ba!]
>> [Xuéle! hǎode, wǒ kāichē, nǐmen zuòchē,
wǒmen yīqǐ qù bādálǐng chángchéng!]
Okay, let's see the answers.
[Chánɡchénɡ de mínɡzi shì?]
[Bādálǐng chángchéng.]
[Bādálǐnɡ chánɡchénɡ zài nǎr?]
[Zài běijīng de xīběi.]
[Tāmen nǎtiān qù chánɡchénɡ?]
[Xīngqīliù.] Now,
[Tāmen zěnme qù?] [Tāmen kāichē qù.]
[Tínɡnà huì kāichē mɑ?]
[Tā huì kāichē.] [Shéi zuòchē?]
[Hǎiliàng hé tóngxuémen.]
Now go over the text with me please.
>> [Zhè shì bādálǐng chángchéng ma?] >> [Shì a.]
>> [Tài měi le! Bādálǐng chángchéng zài nǎr?]
>> [Zài běijīng de xīběi.
Wǒmen jiào jǐ gè tóngxué yīqǐ qù ba?]
>> [Hǎo a! Nǎtiān qù?]
>> [Zhège xīngqīliù zěnme yàng?]
[chánɡchénɡ] is the Great Wall.
[Bādálǐnɡ] is the name of
a section of the Great Wall.
There are also Mutianyu Chanɡchenɡ,
Sīmatai Chanɡcheng etc. in Beijing.
[měi] is beautiful.
[Wǒmen kéyǐ shuō, chánɡchénɡ hěn měi.]
[Nàɡe nǚrén hěn měi], [Hànzì hěn měi] and so on.
[xīběi] is northwest.
[xī] is west,
[běi] is north, [dōnɡ] is east,
[nán] is south.
[jǐɡè], several, a few.
We learnt [jǐ] in
[jǐ diǎn] [xīnɡqī jǐ], but this one is different.
For example, [Shūbāo lǐ yǒu jǐ ɡè pínɡɡuǒ.]
This sentence is a statement which means
there are a few apples in the school bag.
However, if you raise the intonation a bit,
the sentence becomes a question, that is
[Shūbāo lǐ yǒu jǐ ɡè pínɡɡuǒ?]
Okay, go on with the text.
>> [Hǎo, wǒmen zěnme qù ne?]
>> [Nǐ xuéhuì kāichē le ma? Wǒmen kāichē qù ba!]
>> [wǒ xué huì kāi chē le. Hǎode, wǒ kāichē,
nǐmen zuòchē, wǒmen yīqǐ qù bādálǐng chángchéng!]
Sentences like [Wǒmen jiào jǐ ɡè tónɡxué yìqǐ qù bɑ!]
is called pivotal sentence.
A pivotal sentence has two predicates.
The first of which has an object that serves
as the subject for the second predicate.
The structure is, subject + verb 1
+ pivotal word + verb 2 + object.
For example, [wǒ qǐng péngyou lái chīfàn].
[Tā jiào nǚ‘ér xiě hànzì].
[ne] can be with questions.
Involving interrogative pronouns,
like [nǎr], [shéi], [zěnme], [shénme] etc.
to soften the tone of the question.
The structure is,
interrogative pronoun + [ne].
For example, [wǒ men zěnme qù ne?]
[Tāmen zuò shénme ne?]
[Wǒ de hànyǔ shū zài nǎr ne?]
Time flies.
Six weeks passed since you've
started to learn Chinese with me.
Hope you'll find that this
course useful and enjoyable.
I sincerely hope you can keep
going with your Chinese study.
My colleagues from the School of
Chinese as a second language of
Peking University will continue to teach
you for higher levels in the near future.
[Xièxie nǐmen! Tónɡxuémen, zàijiàn!]