[MUSIC]
On our planet one out of
five people is Chinese.
Chinese civilization has a long history, and
China has made great
changes in recent years.
If you would like to communicate
with 1.4 billion people,
if you're curious about
the fascinating culture,
please join us in Chinese for HSK.
[MUSIC]
HSK is the most important Chinese
proficiency test in use today.
At the end of six weeks, you'll
be able to understand and
use simple Chinese phrases,
meet basic needs for communication
and possess the ability to further
your Chinese language studies.
Whether you will take the exam or not,
please follow us to discover
a new language and a new world.
Have a fantastic journey
of Chinese learning.
See you soon.
[Zàijiàn!]