[MUSIC]
[Tónɡxuémen hǎo! Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.
Nǐ xiǎnɡ lái Běijīnɡ mɑ？Nǐ zěnme lái Běijīnɡ?]
[Nǐ yào zuò fēijī lái mɑ? Wǒ de pénɡyou lái le，
tā shì jīntiān shànɡwǔ jiǔdiǎn lái de,]
[tā shì dǎchē lái de. Hé pénɡyou zài yìqǐ,
wǒ hěn ɡāoxìnɡ!]
In this lesson,
we're going to learn directions.
The title of the lesson is
[wǒ de xiǎo māo ne?]
Before watching a video,
let's go over the new words.
[zhuōzi] [yǐzi]
[shūbāo] [shàngmiàn] [xiàmiàn] [hòumiàn]
[shū] is book, [bāo] is bag.
So [shūbāo] is school bag.
[shànɡmiàn] and [xiàmiàn] are opposite words.
On the table [zěnme shuō]?
[Zài zhuōzi shànɡmiàn.]
Under the chair [zěnme shuō]?
[Zài yǐzi xiàmiàn.]
[hòumiàn], What is the opposite
word of [hòumiàn]? It's [qiánmiàn].
Do you remember how to say outside?
Yes, it's [wàimiàn].
And inside?
It's [lǐmiàn].
An exercise for you.
Match the sentences with the pictures.
[Bēizi zài zhuōzi shàngmiàn.]
[Māo zài yǐzi xiàmiàn.]
[Shū zài shūbāo lǐmiàn.]
[Tāmen zài fàndiàn qiánmiàn.]
[Gǒu zài kàn hòumiàn.]
Okay? Let's see the answers.
1D, 2A,
3B,
4E,
5C.
[Nǐ zuò duì le mɑ?]
Video time.
Huanhuan is looking for her cat.
Tingna will tell her where it is.
Listen and pay attention to
the details below.
>> [Tíngnà, wǒ de xiǎomāo ne? Nǐ kànjiàn le ma?]
>> [Kànjiàn le, zài zhuōzi shàngmiàn.]
>> [Zhuōzi shàngmiàn méiyǒu a!]
>> [Zài shū de hòumiàn?]
>> [Nàr yě méiyǒu a!]
>> [Ó, zài yǐzi xiàmiàn.] >>[Méiyǒu a!]
>> [Kàn! Nà shì nǐ de xiǎomāo.]
[Zài shūbāo lǐmiàn.]
Okay, let's see the answers.
Firstly, Tingna said xiaomao is,
a [Zài zhuōzi shànɡmiàn]
Finally, where is the cat?
c [Zài shūbāo lǐmiàn]
Now, read the text with me.
>> [Tíngnà, wǒ de xiǎomāo ne? Nǐ kànjiàn le ma?]
>> [Kànjiàn le, zài zhuōzi shàngmiàn.]
>> [Zhuōzi shàngmiàn méiyǒu a!]
>> [Zài shū de hòumiàn.]
>> [Méiyǒu a!]
>> [Ó, zài yǐzi xiàmiàn.] >>[Méiyǒu a!]
>> [Kàn! Nà shì nǐ de xiǎomāo.]
[Zài shūbāo lǐmiàn.]
Another exercise for you.
Fill in the gaps with suitable words.
Okay, let's see the answers.
1E, 2C, 3A, 4B, 5D.
[Nǐ dá duì le mɑ?]
This type of question is the same
as part four, Reading comprehension,
HSK test, level one.
There are five items in part four.
Each item will display a sentence
with one word missing.
You need to select one of the words in
the answer section to fill in the blank.
Till now, I have introduced all
of the eight question types for
the HSK test, level one.
I hope you find this helpful, whether
you will take the test or not.
Time is up.
Hope you enjoyed the lesson.
Looking forward to seeing you next time.
[Xièxie! Zàijiàn!]