[SOUND]
[Tónɡxuémen hǎo! Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.]
[Nǐ xǐhuɑn zuò shénme? Nǐ xǐhuɑn qù kāfēitīnɡ mɑ?]
[Nǐ xǐhuɑn zài kāfēitīnɡ kànshū mɑ?
Nǐ xǐhuɑn kàn shénme shū?]
[Wǒ hěn xǐhuɑn qù kāfēitīnɡ.
Wǒ xǐhuɑn zài kāfēitīnɡ kànshū.]
[yě xǐhuɑn zài nàlǐ jiàn pénɡyou.]
The lesson for today is [Wǒ ài kàn diànyǐnɡ.].
[ài] means love or like.
Xiaobei and Xiaopei will talk about
what they like and dislike.
Let's watch a video.
>> [Xiǎobèi, nǐ xǐhuān kàn diànshì ma?]
>> [Diànshì ya? Wǒ bù ài kàn.]
>> [Diànyǐng ne? Nǐ ài kàn ma?]
>> [Ài kàn, wǒ yǒu shíhòu zài jiā lǐ kàn diànyǐng,
yǒu shíhòu qù diànyǐng yuàn.]
>> [Ó, nǐ ài kàn shénme diànyǐng?
zhōngguó de, wàiguó de?]
>> [Zhōngguó de hé wàiguó de wǒ dōu xǐhuān.
Nǐ zuì xǐhuān zuò shénme?]
>> [Wǒ zuì xǐhuān dǎ qiú.]
Okay?
What activities they mentioned
in their conversation?
Three.
[kàn diànshì] [kàn diànyǐng] [dǎqiú]
[Tāmen zài dǎqiú.]
Who loves watching films?
[Xiǎobèi xǐhuān kàn diànyǐnɡ.]
Who loves playing ball games?
[Xiǎopéi ài dǎqiú.]
New words from the text.
Read with me, please.
[ài] [yǒushíhòu]
[jiā] [lǐ] [zuì]
[dǎqiú]
[ài] means to love.
I love you, [Zěnmeshuō?]
[Wǒ ài nǐ.]
I love reading, [Zěnmeshuō]?
[Wǒ ài kànshū.]
[yǒushíhou]is sometimes.
[Wǒ yǒushíhou kàn diànyǐnɡ,
yǒushíhou kàn diànshì.]
[jiā] Is home, family, household.
You could say [wǒ jiā], my home.
[Wǒ de jiārén], my family.
[Wǒ ài wǒ jiā], I love my family.
or [Wǒ ài wǒ jiārén.]
[lǐ] means inside.
How do you say at home?
It's [zài jiā lǐ] or [zài jiā].
Inside hospital,
[zài yīyuàn lǐ].
[zuì] is most, best, least, worst.
We could say, [zuì duō, zuì hǎo]
[zuì shǎo, zuì xǐhuɑn], etc.
[dǎ qiú] is play ball games.
You could say, [dǎ lánqiú], play basketball.
[dǎ pīnɡpānɡqiú], play ping pong.
Read the text with me please.
>> [Xiǎobèi, nǐ xǐhuān kàn diànshì ma?]
>> [Diànshì ya? Wǒ bù ài kàn.]
>> [Diànyǐng ne? Nǐ ài kàn ma?]
>> [Ài kàn, wǒ yǒu shíhòu zài jiā lǐ kàn diànyǐng,
yǒu shíhòu qù diànyǐng yuàn.] >> [Ó, nǐ ài kàn
shénme diànyǐng?zhōngguó de, wàiguó de?]
>> [Zhōngguó de hé wàiguó de wǒ dōu xǐhuān.
Nǐ zuì xǐhuān zuò shénme?]
>> [Wǒ zuì xǐhuān dǎ qiú.]
Let's do an exercise now.
Listen to the statements. So, number one,
[Wǒ ài kàn diànshì.]
Number two,
[Tā xīngqī liù qù dǎqiú.]
Number three,
[Wǒ xiǎng qù diànyǐng yuàn kàn diànyǐng].
Number four, [Jiějie xǐhuān kàn shū].
Number five, [Tā de māo zài jiā lǐ].
Please choose one correct answer for each
question. Okay, the answers for you here,
That's one, you choose B.
and 2C, 3A, 4C and 5A.
[Nǐ dá duì le mɑ?]
This type of question is the same as part 2 Listening
of the HSK test, level one. There are 5 items in part 2.
The recording of each item will be played twice.
A sentence and 3 pictures are provided
with each item. You need to choose corresponding pictures
based on what you hear. That's all for today.
See you next time.
[xièxie! Zàijiàn!]