[MUSIC]
[Tónɡxuémen hǎo！Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.]
[Nǐ jīntiān qù xuéxiào le mɑ？Nǐ huì kāichē mɑ？Nǐ xǐhuɑn zǒulù mɑ？]
[Xiàyǔ de shíhou]
[nǐ huì dǎchē huíjiā mɑ？]
[Jīntiān wǒmen xuéxí dì sān kè.]
[FOREIGN] Read the new words with me, please.
[FOREIGN]
[FOREIGN] [fēi] means fly.
[jī] is machine.
[fēijī] is plane.
Flying machine.
[hěn shǎo], very few or very little.
Do you remember how to say many,
or quite a few, is [hěn duō].
[kǎoyā], roast duck, [kǎo]
is to roast. [yā] is duck.  [Běijīnɡ kǎoyā] Beijing
roast duck, is very famous.
[méi]
is the short form of [méiyǒu].
In [Wǒ méiyǒu jiějie. ], [méiyǒu] means don't have.
But [méi] or [méiyǒu]
could be also
used to dictate past actions.
That is to say someone didn't do something or something didn't happen.
For example,
[Shànɡ ɡè yuè wǒ méiyǒu xué zhōnɡwén.]
[zuótiān wǎnshɑnɡ jiějie méi lái.]
Okay, video time.
[Kǎilì de bàbɑ māmɑ lái Běijīnɡ le，tā hěn ɡāoxìnɡ.]
Let's see what she talks about with Xudong.
>> [FOREIGN]
>> Okay.
Let's see the questions and answers.
[Kǎilì de bàbɑ、māmɑ zěnmeyànɡ？] or [Kǎilì de bàbɑ、māmɑ dōu hǎo mɑ？]
[FOREIGN] [Tāmen shì shénme shíhou lái de？] [FOREIGN]
[Tāmen shì zěnme lái de？]
[FOREIGN] [Tāmen xǐhuɑn Běijīnɡ de tiānqì mɑ？]
[FOREIGN]
[Tāmen wèishénme xǐhuɑn Běijīnɡ de tiānqì？]
[FOREIGN].
[Zuótiān tāmen qù chī Běijīnɡ kǎoyā le mɑ？]
[FOREIGN]. [Tāmen shénme shíhou qù fàndiàn？] [FOREIGN].
Now, read the text with me, please.
[FOREIGN]
You need to know a very important
structure in this text.
It is [shì … … de] structure.
You could find related sentences in the text,
like [Tāmen shì nǎtiān lái de？].
[Shànɡ xīnɡqī sān.] Could be the whole sentence
[Tāmen shì shànɡ xīnɡqī sān lái de.]
[Tāmen shì zěnme lái de？]
[Zuò fēijī lái de.] The whole sentence is
[Tāmen shì zuò fēijī lái de.]
The structure is,
Subject + [shì] +
information to be emphasized
+ Verb + [de]. For example,
[FOREIGN]
[shì......de] structure, it's frequently used
when asking details about the past or
telling details about the past.
It can be used to emphasize any detail,
but
mostly time, manner or place.
Can you make more dialogues
with [shì......de] structure?
[Hǎo de，tónɡxuémen，wǒ men yào shuō zàijiàn le. Xièxie nǐmen，mínɡtiān jiàn！]