[MUSIC]
[Tónɡxuémen hǎo！Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.]
[Nǐ jīntiān qù xuéxiào le mɑ?
Nǐ huì kāichē mɑ? Nǐ xǐhuɑn zǒulù mɑ?]
[Xiàyǔ de shíhou,]
[nǐ huì dǎchē huíjiā mɑ?]
[Jīntiān wǒmen xuéxí dì sān kè.]
[Tāmen shì zuò fēijī lái de]
Read the new words with me, please.
[zhèr] [fēijī] [hěn shǎo]
[kǎoyā] [méi]
[fàndiàn]
[fēi] means fly.
[jī] is machine.
[fēijī] is plane.
Flying machine.
[hěn shǎo], very few or very little.
Do you remember how to say many,
or quite a few? It's [hěn duō].
[kǎoyā], roast duck.
[kǎo] is to roast.
[yā] is duck.  [Běijīnɡ kǎoyā],
Beijing roast duck. It's very famous.
[méi], is the short form of [méiyǒu].
In [wǒ méiyǒu jiějie],
[méiyǒu] means don't have.
But [méi] or [méiyǒu] could be also
used to dictate past actions.
That is to say someone didn't do something
or something didn't happen.
For example, [Shànɡ ɡè yuè wǒ méiyǒu xué zhōnɡwén.]
[zuótiān wǎnshɑnɡ jiějie méi lái.]
Okay, video time.
[Kǎilì de bàbɑ māmɑ lái Běijīnɡ le，Tā hěn ɡāoxìnɡ.]
Let's see what she talks about with Xudong.
>> [Xùdōng, wǒ bàba māma lái běijīng le.]
>> [Ò, nǐ bàba māma dōu hǎo me?]
>> [Ǹg, dōu hǎo. Tāmen zài zhèr hěn gāoxìng.]
>> [Tāmen shì nǎtiān lái de?]
>> [Shàng xīngqīsān.]
>> [Tāmen shì zěnme lái de?]
>> [Tāmen shì zuò fēijī lái de.]
>> [Tāmen xǐhuan běijīng de tiānqì ma?]
>> [Ǹg, hěn xǐhuan. Běijīng hěn shǎo xiàyǔ,
tāmen hěn gāoxìng.]
>> [Nǐmen qù chī běijīng kǎoyā le ma?]
>> [Méi qù, wǒmen míngtiān qù fàndiàn
chī běijīng kǎoyā.] >> [Ǹg.]
Okay.
Let's see the questions and answers.
[Kǎilì de bàbɑ māmɑ zěnmeyànɡ?] or
[Kǎilì de bàbɑ māmɑ dōuhǎo mɑ?]
[Dōuhǎo.] [Tāmen shì shénme shíhou lái de?]
[Tāmen shì shàng xīngqīsān lái de.]
[Tāmen shì zěnme lái de?]
[Tāmen shì zuò fēijī lái de.]
[Tāmen xǐhuɑn Běijīnɡ de tiānqì mɑ?]
[Xǐhuɑn.]
[Tāmen wèishénme xǐhuɑn Běijīnɡ de tiānqì?]
[Běijīng hěnshǎo xiàyǔ.]
[Zuótiān tāmen qù chī Běijīnɡ kǎoyā le mɑ?]
[Méi qù.]
[Tāmen shénme shíhou qù fàndiàn?]
[Tāmen míngtiān qù fàndiàn.]
Now, read the text with me, please.
>> [Xùdōng, wǒ bàba māma lái běijīng le.]
>> [Tāmen dōu hǎo me?]
>> [Dōu hǎo. Tāmen zài zhèr hěn gāoxìng.]
>> [Tāmen shì nǎtiān lái de?]
>> [Shàng xīngqīsān.]
>> [Tāmen shì zěnme lái de?]
>> [Zuò fēijī lái de.]
>> [Tāmen xǐhuan běijīng de tiānqì ma?]
>> [Xǐhuan. Běijīng hěn shǎo xiàyǔ,
tāmen hěn gāoxìng.]
>> [Nǐmen qù chī běijīng kǎoyā le ma?]
>> [Méi qù, wǒmen míngtiān qù fàndiàn
chī kǎoyā.]
You need to know a very important structure in this text.
It is [shì … … de] structure.
You could find related sentences in the text,
like [Tāmen shì nǎtiān lái de?]
[Shànɡ xīnɡqī sān.]
Could be the whole sentence,
[Tāmen shì shànɡ xīnɡqī sān lái de.]
[Tāmen shì zěnme lái de?]
[Zuò fēijī lái de.]
The whole sentence is
[Tāmen shì zuò fēijī lái de.]
The structure is,
Subject + [shì] + information to be emphasized
+ Verb + [de]. For example,
[Nǐ shì shénme shíhou lái de?]
[Wǒ shì shàngxīngqī lái de.]
[Nǐ shì zěnme lái de?]
[Wǒ shì zuò chūzū chē lái de.]
[Nǐ shì zài nǎr xué de zhōngwén?]
[Wǒ shì zài běijīng dàxué xué de zhōngwén.]
[shì......de] structure, is frequently used
when asking details about the past or
telling details about the past.
It can be used to emphasize any detail,
but mostly time, manner or place.
Can you make more dialogues
with [shì......de] structure?
[Hǎode tónɡxuémen，Wǒmen yào shuō zàijiàn le.
Xièxie nǐmen，Mínɡtiān jiàn!]