[MUSIC]
[FOREIGN]
You can
tell me your
daily routine
in Chinese now.
That's great.
Today we're going to learn the days
of the week and the birthdays.
To ask what day of the week
is it today is [FOREIGN].
[FOREIGN] means week in Chinese.
This is also used to indicate which
weekday you're talking about.
It's much easier to say days of
the week in Chinese than in English.
They are formed by the words
week followed by a number.
For example, Monday is [FOREIGN].
Tuesday is [FOREIGN].
What about Wednesday?
Yes, it's [FOREIGN].
Here is the table.
Read after me, please.
[FOREIGN]
or
[FOREIGN].
As you can see,
Sunday is an exception.
It's [FOREIGN] or [FOREIGN].
You can't say [FOREIGN].
To answer the question [FOREIGN],
you just need to replace the date
with the question word, [FOREIGN].
For example,
[FOREIGN].
Let's watch a video.
Tell me the day and
the time they mention in the video.
>> [FOREIGN]
>> Okay?
[FOREIGN]
What are they talking about?
You may have heard [FOREIGN].
A new word for
you is [FOREIGN] which means to go.
Read the whole conversation with me,
please.
[FOREIGN]
For
the question
[FOREIGN],
are you going
to school or
university?
The answer is [FOREIGN].
In Chinese, we often use the verb
from the question for the answer.
For example, [FOREIGN].
If yes, you say [FOREIGN].
If not, you say [FOREIGN].
The answer could be [FOREIGN] or
[FOREIGN].
In Chinese,
a sentence with the nominal predicate is
a sentence whose predicate
is nominal element.
It's usually used to indicate age,
time, date, and so on.
For example
[FOREIGN]
There are a couple of new
words in dialogue two.
Read after me please.
[FOREIGN].
Xiao Bei and are talking about birthday.
Listen to them and pay attention to
Xiao Bei's birthday in the video.
>> [FOREIGN]
>> [FOREIGN].
>> When is Xiao Bei's birthday?
[FOREIGN]
Are you
correct?
Please read the text with me.
[FOREIGN]
means
which
date?
You could also say [FOREIGN] means
which month, which date?
In Chinese days follow the order year,
month, day.
This goes from big to
small in Chinese culture.
Look at some examples.
The structure.
[FOREIGN]
Go on with
the text.
[FOREIGN]
That's
all for today,
I hope you enjoyed
the lesson, [FOREIGN]