[MUSIC]
[Nǐ hǎo！Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.]
[Wǒ jiào Yú Bīn. Wǒ de diànhuà hàomǎ shì bā liù yāo ling liù èr qī wǔ(8610 6275).]
[nǐ de diànhuà hàomǎ shì duōshao?]
We are going to learn
more greetings today.
So you could use the phrases
over the weekend,
if you have Chinese friends around.
There are five dialogues.
Dialogue 1, read after me, please.
[Tóngxué men hǎo!].
[Lǎoshī hǎo!]
Almost every day when I step
into my classroom I say,
[Tóngxué men hǎo] to my students.
And my students say, [Lǎoshī hǎo] to me.
[Tóngxué men] is students or classmates.
[Lǎoshī]is teacher.
To make personal pronouns
including [Wǒ, nǐ, tā],
and [tā] plural.
all you need to do is add to the suffix
[men] to it.
Please have a look.
[wǒ men].
[nǐ men].
[tā men].
When you use suffix [men],
it's only for people.
Not for any other things.
Read with me please,
[wǒ men].[nǐ men].[tā men].[tā men].
For instance we can say, [tóngxué men].
And [hànzì men], no, you can't say that.
What about [péngyou men]?
Yeah, of course.
How about [gǒu men]?
No.
Now let's watch a video.
—— [Nǐ zěnmeyàng?]
—— [Wǒ hěn hǎo. Nǐ ne?]
—— [Wǒ yě hěn hǎo.]
—— The first sentence in the video is
[nǐ zěnmeyàng?], how are you?
[zěnmeyàng] is used to ask about
the condition of something or someone.
More examples.
[Tā zěnmeyàng?]
[Tiānqì zěnmeyàng?]
[Zhè ge zěnmeyàng?]
Read the text from dialogue one.
[nǐ zěnmeyàng?].
[Wǒ hěn hǎo. Nǐ ne?]
[Wǒ yě hěn hǎo.]
An exercise for you now.
Translate the English
phrases into Chinese.
Let's do it together.
Number one, I'm fine.
How do you say that?
Yes, [Wǒ hěn hǎo].
Number two, teacher, students.
[Lǎoshī, tóngxué men].
The last one, how are you?
[Nǐ zěnmeyàng?].
Do you get it?
You may know how to say thank you.
But how do you say, you're welcome?
Have a look, then.
—— [Xièxie!]
—— [Bú kèqi!]
—— [Xièxie] means thank you.
The second [Xiè] in
[Xièxie] is neutral tone.
[Bú kèqi] means you're welcome or
not at all.
[qi] in [Bú kèqi] is also soft tone.
Read after me please.
[Xièxie!][Bú kèqi!]
Dialogue 4 for you.
—— [Oh, Duìbuqǐ!]
—— [Méi guānxi!]
—— What did they say?
Yes, they said, I'm sorry.
That's all right, no problem.
Follow me, please.
[Duìbuqǐ!][Méi guānxi!]
There are two syllables
with a neutral tone.
One is [bù] in [Duìbuqǐ],
another one is [xì] in [Méi guānxi].
The last dialogue for you is,
let's watch a video,
—— [Qiáozhì, zaìjiàn!]
—— [Míngtiān jiàn!]
[Zaìjiàn!][Míngtiān jiàn!]
[zaì] means again.
[jiàn] means to see, you learned
[Míngtiān] in last lesson is tomorrow.
So the two phrases are see you again,
see you tomorrow.
Read with me again please.
[Zaìjiàn!][Míngtiān jiàn!]
That's all for today.
[Xièxie!]
[Zaìjiàn!]