[MUSIC]
[Tónɡxuémen hǎo！Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.]
[Jīntiān shì jǐ yuè jǐ hào？Jīntiān xīnɡqī jǐ？]
[Nǐ de shēnɡrì shì jǐ yuè jǐ hào？] 'Happy birthday!' [zěnme shuō]?
Can you sing the song
'happy birthday' in Chinese?
In this lesson we're going
to learn some new words and
expressions about weather in Chinese.
Listen to dialogue one.
>> [FOREIGN]
>> What are they talking about?
Yes, the weather.
Let's read the text.
[FOREIGN]
[tiānqì] is
weather.
[yǔ] Is rain.
The meaning of the question is
what is the weather like tomorrow?
And the answer word by
word is not very good.
Tomorrow has rain.
Read again with me, please.
[FOREIGN]
Now listen to dialog two.
>> [FOREIGN]
>> From the picture,
you may guess what is happening now.
Yes, it's raining, but
the computer is outside.
Read the text with me, please.
[FOREIGN]
Again.
[Xià yǔ le]
means
it's raining, like we
learned some time ago,
[le] indicates change of situation or
starting a new situation.
[diànnǎo] is computer and
[wàimiàn] is outside.
In a sentence [Wǒ de diànnǎo zài wàimiàn ne！], [zài] is a verb.
expressing existence in a location
similar to how we say in
English, 'to be at' or 'to be in'.
For example,
[FOREIGN].
In dialog three,
it mentions two places in China One
is Guangzhou a big city in Southern China.
Harbin a city in the Northeast.
Let's learn some new words.
[FOREIGN]
We're going
to listen to
dialogue three.
Pay attention to the weather
in the two cities.
>> [FOREIGN]
>> [FOREIGN].
>> [Guǎnɡzhōu de tiānqì zěnmeyànɡ？].
The answer
[Tài rè le！] [Tài rè le！]
[Hā ěr bīn de tiānqì zěnmeyànɡ？]
[Yǒu diǎnr lěnɡ.] [Yǒu diǎnr lěnɡ.]
[yǒu diǎnr] a little, a bit.
Usually indicating something unpleasant or
undesired.
The structure is [yǒu diǎnr] + adjective or
psychological verb.
Examples here.
[FOREIGN]
Read the whole text of dialogue
three with me, please.
[FOREIGN]
An exercise for you.
Listen.
>> Number 1.
[FOREIGN]
Number 2.
Number 3.
[FOREIGN]
Number 4.
Number 5.
[FOREIGN]
>> Okay, let's see the answers.
[Nǐ dá duì le mɑ？]
Are you correct?
That's all for today.
Hope you enjoyed the lesson.
[Xièxie! Zàijiàn!]