[Nǐ hǎo！Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.]
[Wǒ jiào Yú Bīn. Wǒ shì Zhōnɡɡuó rén. Nǐ shì nǎɡuórén?]
Can you tell me your country's name in Chinese?
[Yīngguó, Hánguó, Āijí, Àodàlìyà?]
In this lesson, we're going to learn how to count numbers
and talk about people's ages in Chinese.
Follow me to read 1 to 10 please.
[Yī, yī]
[èr, èr]
[sān, sān]
[sì, sì]
[wǔ, wǔ]
[liù, liù]
[qī, qī]
[bā, bā]
[jiǚ, jiǚ]
[shí, shí]
On top, the number is
[líng, líng]
Wow, so many pandas.
[Dàxióngmāo]
Let's read it.
[Yī, yī]
[èr, èr]
[sān, sān]
[sì, sì]
[wǔ, wǔ]
[liù, liù]
[qī, qī]
[bā, bā]
[jiǔ, jiǔ]
The last picture,
[shí, shí]
Numbers above 10 are easy to remember,
you just say [ten one, ten two] et cetera.
[Shí yī, shí èr]
Let's see some more numbers.
Read the list with me, please.
[Shí yī]
[Shí èr]
[èr shí]
[èr shí sān]
[sān shí sì]
[sì shí qī]
[wǔ shí liù]
[liù shí jiǔ]
[qī shí bā]
[bā shí wǔ]
[jiù shí jiǔ]
How do you ask someone's age in Chinese?
Here is a video for you.
>> [Xùdōng, nǐ duō dà le?]
>> [Wǒ èr shí sì suì. Nǐ ne?]
>> [Wǒ èr shí yi suì. Tā duǒ dà le?]
>> [Tā shí bā suì.]
Did you hear the age of these three people?
[èr shí sì]
[èr shí yī]
[shí bā]
[Nǐ duō dà le?]
How old are you?
[Duo da] means how old.
[Le] is used at the end of a sentence to
indicate change of state.
In other words, there's now a new situation
or there is about to be a new situation.
[Suì] means year.
For the answer to the question,
[nǐ duō dà le?]
you say, [wǒ], plus your age
and then [suì].
Read after me please.
[Nǐ duō dà le?] [Nǐ duō dà le?]
[Wǒ èr shí sì suì.]
[Nǐ ne?]
[Wǒ èr shí yī suì.]
[Tā duō dà le?] [Tā duō dà le?]
[Tā shí bā suì.]
Have you noticed there is a [ne]
after [nǐ]? What is it?
[Ne] is a particle which can be used
to ask reciprocal questions,
also known as bounce-back questions.
[Ne] can be used to form simple questions
asking what about or how about.
The structure is, topic plus [ne].
For example, [Nǐ duō dà le?]
[Wǒ shí liù suì. Nǐ ne?]
[Wǒ èr shí qī suì.]
[Nǐ shì nǎ ɡuó rén?]
[Wǒ shì Zhōnɡɡuó rén. nǐ ne?]
We have learned [nǐ, wǒ, tā.]
Interestingly, the pronunciation for he
is the same as for she.
So, when I say [tā],
you actually don't know if I'm talking
about him or her.
That is really tricky, isn't it?
However, in writing, we don't have this
problem because they are different characters.
Have a look, [tā, tā.]
Now, let's do an exercise.
Listen to three statements.
The question is how old are they?
Number one, [Tā jiào Àobāmǎ.
Tā wǔ shí sì suì.]
Number two, [Tā jiào Zhāng Zǐyí.
Tā sān shí qī suì.]
Number three. [Tā jiào Lín Shūháo.
Tā èr shí bā suì.]
Okay. Can you tell me
[Tāmén duō dà le]?
Okay, let's see the answer,
[Àobāmǎ duō dà le? Àobāmǎ wǔ shí sì suì.]
[Zhāng Zǐyí duō dà le? Tā sān shí qī suì.]
The last person,
[Lín Shūháo duō dà le? Tā èr shí bā suì.]
Did you get it?
We have learned so much today.
Have a good rest.
[Xièxie! Zàijiàn!]