[MUSIC]
[FOREIGN]
For each time
when I start a new lesson,
I will ask you a couple
of questions from
the last lesson.
Please try to give me you
answers to the questions.
Today, we are going to talk
about Chinese learning.
George, Chinese name [FOREIGN] has
a younger brother who is proud of himself.
Why?
You will find out after watching a video.
Before that, let's go over the new words.
Read after me please.
[FOREIGN]
is
can.
How do you say cannot?
It's [FOREIGN] We learned
[FOREIGN] By itself,
[FOREIGN] means no, not.
Not good is [FOREIGN].
Not happy is [FOREIGN]
a little.
I can speak a little Chinese.
[FOREIGN]
is cool.
It's translated according to
the sound of the English word cool.
[FOREIGN] means correct, right.
When we say yes in Chinese,
we say [FOREIGN] more than [FOREIGN].
[FOREIGN]
means
very,
too.
In between [FOREIGN] and the [FOREIGN]
you could place an adjective or
a psychological verb.
For example, [FOREIGN]
means how.
How to speak is [FOREIGN]
How to write is [FOREIGN]
How to read is [FOREIGN] is
the name of my university.
Peking University.
Okay, we do term.
—— [FOREIGN]
—— Okay, what did you hear?
Who can speak Chinese?
[FOREIGN]
Can he write
any Chinese
characters?
[FOREIGN]
I will play the video again.
Please pay attention to
the questions below.
Number one.
—— [FOREIGN]
—— [FOREIGN] Let's read this
through the whole text.
—— [FOREIGN]
A fruitful lesson, isn't it?
That's all for today.
Have a nice rest.
—— [FOREIGN]