[MUSIC]
[Tónɡxué men hǎo！Huānyínɡ láidào HSK hànyǔ kètánɡ.Nǐ yǒu ɡǒu mɑ？]
Nǐ yǒu māo mɑ？Nǐ de ɡǒu jiào shénme mínɡzi？]
[Nǐ de māo duōdà le?][Wǒ méiyǒu ɡǒu.]
[yě méiyǒu māo.] Actually, when I was young
[Wǒ yǒu ɡǒu，wǒ yě yǒu māo.]
Today we are going to read an e-mail from Lucy to Jenny.
Both Lucy and
Jenny are learning Chinese now.
Listen to Lucy carefully.
Tell me what kind of
information you've got.
—— Jenny,
[FOREIGN].
Lucy.
—— Lucy mentioned three
people in her email.
[Tāmen duōdà le?] One is [FOREIGN]
One is [FOREIGN] And
the last one is [FOREIGN]. Who are they then? A little
later you'll be clearer
about the content of the email.
The first sentence from the email
is [FOREIGN] Beijng [FOREIGN] I'm
learning Chinese in Beijing.
[zài] Followed by a location,
comes before a wprd. It is to indicate the location
where an action or activity takes place.
This is one case that Chinese word
order is quite different from English.
The structure is subject, + [zài],
+ Place + Verb + Object.
More examples, [FOREIGN]
Elder brother works in China.
[FOREIGN]
Younger sister
travels in America.
[Běijīnɡ] is the capital city of China.
[xuéxí] means to learn or to study.
[hànyǔ] is Chinese language.
We have learnt [ne] in [nǐ ne], but this
[ne] is very different.
In this sentence [ne] is to indicate
that an action is ongoing or in progress.
For example,
you could say [FOREIGN].
[FOREIGN]
And
the structure
is here.
Okay?
Let's read the whole text.
Jenny
[FOREIGN]
Lucy.
Here are some more new words
[xuéxiào] is school or university.
[ɡè] is the most commonly
used measure word in Chinese.
You can say [yí ɡè rén，yí ɡè lǎoshī，yí ɡè diànhuà]
[érzi]is son], [nǚ'ér]
is daughter,
[FOREIGN]
[hé] means and.
Read after me please.
[FOREIGN].
Can you give me more examples
by using [hé] to connect two words.
I have got three, you may have more.
[FOREIGN]
mama,
papa, [FOREIGN]
mama, [FOREIGN]
Let's do an exercise.
Which two words are related
with your family?
Which two words are related to education?
Which two words are places?
Let's have a look.
[FOREIGN]
Place.
Family [FOREIGN]
Education.
That's all for today.
Looking forward to seeing you next time.
[Xièxie! Zàijiàn!]